♪
Eugeo: ALICE?
( Kirito gasps )
Eugeo: ALICE,
IT’S YOU, ISN’T IT?
( groans )
Kirito: EUGEO!
Alice:
CHOOSE YOUR ACTIONS CAREFULLY.
I HAVE THE RIGHT TO REMOVE UP TO
70% OF YOUR LIFE IF I WISH IT,
AND IF YOU TOUCH ME AGAIN
WITHOUT MY PERMISSION,
I WILL HAVE YOUR HAND.
Eugeo: ALICE.
Kirito: ARE YOU SURE?
’CAUSE IT’S BEEN A WHILE
SINCE YOU SAW HER.
Eugeo: MM-HMM.
Kirito: THEN WE DO
WHAT SHE SAYS...
FOR NOW.
WE CAN ARGUE
OUR CASE WITH HER
AFTER WE GET
INSIDE THE CENTRAL CATHEDRAL.
Alice: ENOUGH DELAYS.
NOW, ELITE DISCIPLE EUGEO,
ELITE DISCIPLE KIRITO,
YOU ARE IN VIOLATION
OF THE TABOO INDEX.
I WILL TAKE YOU INTO CUSTODY,
THEN QUESTION YOU,
THEN EXECUTE YOU.
♪
♪ SHINY SWORD, MY DIAMOND ♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ IT’S TIME ♪
♪
( Kirito grunts )
( girls panting )
( Eugeo gasps )
TIESE!
Kirito: RONIE!
Tiese: L-LADY KNIGHT,
FORGIVE OUR INTRUSION
Ronie: WE’D LIKE TO RETURN THESE
TO OUR MENTORS
WITH YOUR PERMISSION.
Alice: VERY WELL. HOWEVER,
I CANNOT ALLOW THESE CRIMINALS
TO CARRY WEAPONS.
I WILL LOOK AFTER THEM.
( Ronie stammers )
Alice: YOU HAVE ONE MINUTE.
SPEAK WITH THEM, IF YOU WISH.
( girls gasp )
Tiese: I’M SORRY, EUGEO.
YOU SHOULDN’T EVEN BE
IN THIS MESS.
I SHOULD. THIS IS MY FAULT.
I WAS DUMB.
I ACTED SO RECKLESSLY.
Eugeo: STOP IT.
YOU’RE NOT TO BLAME.
YOU DID THE RIGHT THING.
YOUR FRIEND WAS IN TROUBLE,
AND YOU DID
WHAT YOU COULD TO HELP.
WHAT HAPPENED IS MY FAULT,
NOT YOURS.
( Tiese whimpers )
Eugeo: YOU HAVE NOTHING
TO BE SORRY ABOUT EVER.
Tiese: I PROMISE,
WHATEVER IT TAKES,
I’LL BECOME
AN INTEGRITY KNIGHT,
AND THEN I’LL BE THE ONE
TO COME AND SAVE YOU,
AND I WON’T STOP UNTIL I DO.
’TIL THEN, DON’T GIVE UP HOPE!
I SWEAR I’LL SAVE YOU!
Ronie: UM,
I BROUGHT YOU SOME LUNCH.
Kirito: UH...
( chains rattle )
Ronie: MAKE SURE TO EAT IT
BEFORE IT SPOILS.
- Kirito: THANKS, RON--
- ( Ronie gasps )
Alice: IT IS TIME. STEP AWAY.
♪
Tiese: NO.
( wings flapping )
♪
Asuna: I WISH THEY’D LET ME
DIVE IN THERE WITH YOU.
MAYBE I COULD GET YOU OUT.
♪
- ( grinding )
- ( footsteps clanking )
OH, EXCUSE ME.
( gasps )
A-A ROBOT!
( whimpers )
Higa: HEY!
YOU’RE SCARIN’ HER, ICHIEMON!
Asuna: WH-WHAT DID YOU
CALL THIS THING JUST NOW?
Higa: HIS NAME. WHAT ELSE?
HE’S ICHIEMON,
AN ELECTROACTIVE MUSCLED
OPERATIVE MACHINE, OR "EMOM."
HE’S ALSO THE FIRST
OF HIS TYPE,
SO, LIKE, WE ADDED
THE "ICHI" AT THE TOP.
"ICHIEMON." GET IT?!
Asuna: A-AND WHAT IS
THIS ICHIEMON DOING ONBOARD?
Higa: WELL, HE’S SOR--
Rinko: I’M USING IT
TO FINE-TUNE A PROGRAM,
AND HIGA HERE
IS GIVING ME HAND WITH IT.
WE’RE LAB PARTNERS AGAIN,
JUST LIKE IN COLLEGE.
( Asuna chuckles ) GOOD MORNING.
Rinko: MORNING. YOU SLEEP WELL?
♪
YOUR PROBLEM IS ITS BALANCER’S
PROCESSOR RUNS SLOW.
CAN’T YOU BUY A FASTER CHIP?
IT’S NOT LIKE
YOU DON’T HAVE THE BUDGET TO.
Higa: YEAH,
BUT COOLING AND BATTERY DRAIN
WOULD STILL BE A PROBLEM.
CONSIDERING THAT, THIS IS
THE BEST THAT WE CAN DO.
ONE OTHER OPTION WOULD BE
TO TUNE THE E.A.P. ACTUATOR
TO PICK UP THE SLACK.
Rinko: SURE,
BUT THE POLYMER MUSCLES
ARE LAST GEN, SO THERE’S THAT.
UPGRADE TO C.N.T.s.
THEY’LL TAKE THE STRAIN BETTER
AND MAKE IT LIGHTER.
Asuna: HMM?
Rinko: UH...
WE’RE IN OUR OWN WORLD
OVER HERE.
SORRY ABOUT THE NOISE.
Asuna: THAT’S OKAY.
IF KIRITO WERE HERE,
HE’D GET A BIG KICK
OUT OF THIS ROBOT OF YOURS.
Higa: ACTUALLY, WE BUILT HIM
’CAUSE THE COMANDANTE
WANTED US TO.
Asuna: WAIT. KIKUOKA DID?
WH-WHAT FOR?
Rinko: IT’S A NEAT IDEA,
ACTUALLY,
BUT I’M NOT SURE
HOW SERIOUS HE IS ABOUT IT YET.
ULTIMATELY, HIS GOAL
IS TO BRING FLUCTLIGHTS
FROM THE UNDERWORLD
INTO OUR WORLD,
BUT THE CATCH IS
THEY’RE GOING TO NEED
SOMETHING
THEY CAN MOVE AROUND IN.
Asuna: SO WAIT.
THE PLAN IS
TO PUT THE A.I.s IN THAT?
Higa: NOT THIS GUY. HE’S JUST
A PROTOTYPE FOR DATA COLLECTION.
WE HAVE A SECOND ROBOT
WITH ONBOARD A.I.
THAT’S WAY MORE ADVANCED.
HE OPERATES
A HECK OF A LOT SMOOTHER.
Asuna: OH, YOU DON’T SAY?
I WONDER WHAT YOU DECIDED
TO CALL THAT ONE.
Higa: NIEMON, OF COURSE!
Asuna: "NI" WHAT? OH.
RIGHT, "NI" MEANS TWO.
ANYWAY, WHY DOES
HAVING ONBOARD A.I.
IN THIS OTHER ROBOT
MAKE IT BETTER?
Rinko: FOR US TO BALANCE,
OUR BRAINS MAKE
LOTS OF MICROADJUSTMENTS.
TO REPLICATE THAT MECHANICALLY
WOULD TAKE A LOT OF TECH
AND A BIGGER BODY
TO HOUSE IT ALL IN.
Asuna: OH.
SO IF A FLUCTLIGHT IS PILOTING
INSTEAD OF A CPU,
THE ROBOT CAN MOVE MORE LIKE
A HUMAN AND ALSO BE SMALLER.
Higa: BINGO! AND THE SMALLER
THE TECH INSIDE,
THE CLOSER IT CAN LOOK
LIKE A HUMAN BODY,
OR SO WE HOPE.
FOR NOW, HE’S STILL
A WORK IN PROGRESS.
NIEMON’S COMING ALONG, THOUGH.
HE’S LOOKIN’ PRETTY HUMAN.
WELL,
HIS SILHOUETTE DOES, ANYWAY.
Rinko: AND MAYBE
ONE OF THESE DAYS,
I’LL GET TO SEE
THE DAMN THING. WAIT!
YOU HAVEN’T
GOTTEN IT TO WALK AROUND
ON ITS OWN YET, HAVE YOU?
Higa: WHAT?
NO, OF COURSE I HAVEN’T.
HIS CPU IS ALL LOADED UP
AND READY TO GO,
BUT NO ONE’S HOME
TO WORK THE CONTROLS,
IF YOU GET MY DRIFT.
Rinko: OH.
- HEY, ASUNA...
- Asuna: HUH?
Rinko: HAVE YOU
HAD BREAKFAST YET?
Asuna: NO, I HAVEN’T.
Rinko: THEN LET’S GO DOWN
TO THE CAFETERIA TOGETHER.
I’D INVITE HIGA, BUT HE ALREADY
MADE PLANS WITH ICHIEMON.
Higa: BON APPÉTIT, LADIES!
( door whooshes )
( Asuna grunts )
♪
( chuckles ) BACK IN A BIT.
HUH?
♪
( Asuna gasps )
Rinko: SOMETHING WRONG, ASUNA?
Asuna: OH. NO, IT’S NOTHING.
Rinko: COME ON.
♪
( footsteps thumping )
Kirito: WE’VE ONLY BEEN HERE
FOR A DAY AND A HALF,
BUT IT FEELS WAY LONGER.
HEY, HOW YOU DOIN’ OVER THERE?
Eugeo: I DON’T KNOW.
THIS WHOLE THING
FEELS LIKE A NIGHTMARE.
I KEEP SEEING
HUMBERT’S ARM FLYING OFF
AND RAIOS SCREAMING AS HE DIED.
Kirito: GET THAT STUFF
OUT OF YOUR HEAD.
START THINKING ABOUT
WHAT WE’RE GONNA DO NEXT.
Eugeo: I DON’T KNOW
WHAT THAT COULD BE.
YOU KNOW,
YOU’RE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
WE HAVE TO FIND A WAY
TO BREAK OUT OF THIS CELL
AND THEN FIGURE OUT
WHAT HAPPENED TO ALICE.
Kirito: YEAH.
IF THERE’S A WAY OUT
OF THIS PLACE, WE’LL FIND IT.
Eugeo: I WONDER...
DID THEY BRING ALICE HERE
EIGHT YEARS AGO?
Kirito: I DON’T KNOW. MAYBE.
( sighs )
SINCE YOU BROUGHT HER UP,
I JUST WANNA BE SURE
OF SOMETHING.
THE KNIGHT THAT CALLS HERSELF
ALICE SYNTHESIS THIRTY,
YOU’RE POSITIVE THAT SHE’S
THE SAME ALICE
YOU’RE LOOKING FOR?
Eugeo: YEAH, I AM.
THOSE BLUE EYES,
GOLDEN HAIR, AND THAT VOICE,
I’D NEVER FORGET THEM.
BUT SHE SEEMED LIKE
A TOTALLY DIFFERENT PERSON.
Kirito: FOR SOMEONE
WHO’S SUPPOSED TO BE
YOUR CHILDHOOD FRIEND,
SHE WHACKED YOU PRETTY GOOD.
BUT IF YOU WANT MY OPINION,
IT COULD BE
SHE’S UNDER SOME KIND
OF MIND CONTROL OR SOMETHING.
Eugeo: BUT I DON’T REMEMBER
SEEING SPELLS LIKE THAT
IN ANY OF OUR TEXTBOOKS.
Kirito: RIGHT,
BUT THE HIGH-RANKING PRIESTS
IN THE CHURCH
CAN MANIPULATE LIFE.
IF THEY CAN DO THAT, THEY CAN
CONTROL SOMEONE’S MIND, TOO.
ALTHOUGH, IF THAT KNIGHT
REALLY IS YOUR ALICE,
WHOSE VOICE DID I HEAR...
TWO YEARS AGO IN THE CAVE?
Girl: KIRITO, EUGEO,
COME AND FIND ME.
I AM WAITING...
AT THE TOP
OF THE CENTRAL CATHEDRAL.
I WILL WAIT THERE FOR YOU BOTH.
Eugeo: RIGHT. YOU TOLD ME THAT.
WHEN YOU AND SELKA
WERE HEALING ME,
YOU SAID YOU HEARD A VOICE
AND THEN SAW SOMETHING
THAT LOOKED LIKE ALICE.
Kirito: YEAH.
SHE SAID SHE’D WAIT FOR US
AT THE TOP
OF THE CENTRAL CATHEDRAL.
AND NOW WE’RE STUCK.
( gasps )
HEY, DO YOU THINK
WE CAN ACCESS
THE STACIA WINDOWS
ON THESE CHAINS?
Eugeo: I NEVER EVEN
THOUGHT TO TRY THAT.
GIVE IT A SHOT.
Kirito: ’KAY.
WHOA. IT WORKED.
Eugeo: AH, WE COULD PULL
ON THESE CHAINS FOREVER,
AND THEY’D NEVER BUDGE.
IF WE’RE GOING
TO BREAK FREE OF THEM,
WE NEED TO GET OUR HANDS
ON A TOOL OR WEAPON
THAT’S AT LEAST CLASS 38.
( Kirito grunts )
YEAH, THAT WON’T DO ANYTHING.
( sighs )
Eugeo: I KNOW
WHAT YOU’RE THINKING,
BUT THE ONLY THINGS
WE HAVE IN HERE
ARE A COUPLE OF BEDS,
WATER SKINS, AND THESE CHAINS.
Kirito: A PAIR OF CHAINS.
( grunts )
Eugeo: UH...
Kirito: YEAH, YOU’RE RIGHT.
WE GOT THESE CHAINS,
TWO OF THESE SUCKERS,
JUST WHAT WE NEED.
Eugeo: WHAT?
( chains clinking )
HANG ON. I HAVE A QUESTION.
IS YOUR IDEA TO USE THE CHAINS
AGAINST ONE ANOTHER?
Kirito: IT TOTALLY IS.
THESE CHAINS OF OURS HAVE
THE SAME DURABILITY LEVEL.
WE’D NEED SOMETHING
WITH AN OBJECT CONTROL AUTHORITY
OVER 40 TO BREAK ’EM,
BUT IF WE SNAP ’EM
AGAINST EACH OTHER,
THAT SHOULD WEAR ’EM DOWN.
JUST FOLLOW MY LEAD, OKAY?
Eugeo: UH...
Kirito: READY, AND...
HELL, YEAH!
Eugeo: NOT SO LOUD!
- YOU’LL WAKE THE GUARD UP!
- Kirito: UH...
( guard snoring )
( mutters )
( both sigh )
Kirito: LET’S GIVE IT
ANOTHER TRY.
Both: READY, AND...
( Kirito groans )
( Eugeo groans )
I THINK THAT KNOCKED
AT LEAST 100 POINTS OFF MY LIFE.
Kirito:
THAT’S A SMALL PRICE TO PAY
FOR FREEDOM, WOULDN’T YOU SAY?
THINGS ARE LOOKIN’ UP.
Eugeo: MM-HMM.
Kirito: ALL RIGHT, THEN.
IF WE DO THIS,
THERE’S NO GOING BACK FOR US.
REMEMBER,
BY BREAKING OUT OF THIS CELL
AND LOOKING
FOR THE TRUTH ABOUT ALICE,
WE’RE DEFYING THE AXIOM CHURCH
AND ITS LAWS.
THAT MEANS FROM NOW ON,
THERE’S NO TIME
FOR SECOND-GUESSING
OR HESITATION.
YOU BETTER MAKE SURE
YOU’RE PREPARED FOR THAT NOW.
OTHERWISE,
YOU SHOULD STAY HERE.
Eugeo: YEAH, I KNOW.
BUT MY MIND’S MADE UP.
IF I CAN RETURN HOME WITH ALICE,
DEFYING THE CHURCH
ISN’T EVEN A QUESTION.
I’LL EVEN DRAW MY SWORD
AGAINST THEM IF I HAVE TO.
I WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT KNIGHT
IS ALICE, AND, IF SHE IS,
I’LL FIND A WAY TO CHANGE HER
BACK TO THE WAY SHE WAS.
THAT’S THE ONLY THING
THAT MATTERS TO ME,
AND NOTHING WILL STOP ME.
REMEMBER WHAT YOU SAID
ON THAT PICNIC
WITH RONIE AND TIESE?
"THERE ARE THINGS YOU SHOULD DO,
EVEN IF THE LAWS
SAY YOU SHOULDN’T."
I UNDERSTAND
WHAT YOU MEANT BY THAT NOW.
Kirito: ALL RIGHT.
YOU SOUND LIKE YOU’RE READY,
SO LET’S GO GIVE ’EM SOME HELL.
( yells )
SWEET. LET’S GO
BEFORE THE GUARD WAKES UP.
Eugeo: RIGHT.
♪
( guard grumbling )
( snoring )
♪
( Kirito sighs ) DOESN’T LOOK
LIKE ANYONE’S FOLLOWING US.
Eugeo: NO WAY. LOOK AT THAT!
Kirito: WHAT’S UP?
IS SOMEONE COMING?
Eugeo: SEE THESE FLOWERS?
I’VE HEARD OF THEM.
KIRITO, THESE ARE ROSES.
Kirito: OH, YEAH. HUH.
NO WAY! THEY ARE ROSES,
AND THIS PLACE
IS CHOCK-FULL OF ’EM!
Eugeo: IT’S RARE TO FIND ONE,
BUT A WHOLE GARDEN FULL...
I CAN’T BELIEVE
WE’RE STANDING HERE.
YOU AND I ACTUALLY MADE IT
TO THE CENTRAL CATHEDRAL.
Kirito: YEAH. WE’RE CRIMINALS,
NOT INTEGRITY KNIGHTS,
BUT WE’RE HERE,
AND THAT’S ALL THAT MATTERS.
Eugeo: IT’S PROBABLY
FOR THE BEST
THAT THINGS WORKED OUT THIS WAY.
IF WE HAD BECOME
INTEGRITY KNIGHTS,
WE MIGHT HAVE
ENDED UP LIKE ALICE.
Kirito: THEY COULD HAVE
GOTTEN IN OUR HEADS
AND SCREWED
WITH OUR MEMORIES, TOO.
I WONDER, IF THEY DO THAT
TO ALL THE INTEGRITY KNIGHTS,
DO THEY FORGET EVERYTHING
ABOUT WHO THEY WERE BEFORE?
Eugeo: WHO KNOWS?
Kirito: YEAH, WELL,
EVEN IF A KNIGHT’S MEMORIES
GOT BLOCKED SOMEHOW,
THEY’D AT LEAST REMEMBER
THEIR PARENTS OR
THE PLACE WHERE THEY WERE BORN.
STUFF LIKE THAT’S
BAKED INTO A PERSON’S SOUL.
IT’D BE IMPOSSIBLE TO SWAP OUT
THOSE KIND OF DETAILS
WITH FAKE ONES.
Eugeo: YOU HAVE A POINT.
THOSE FAKE MEMORIES
WOULD LIKELY BE TENUOUS AT BEST.
WHAT IF THEY WERE
FLYING AROUND WHILE ON DUTY
AND CAME UPON
THE PLACE THEY GREW UP?
ONCE THEY SAW IT,
THEY WOULD KNOW,
AND ALL THEIR MEMORIES
WOULD COME--( gasps )
Kirito: WHAT?
( sighs ) NOT AGAIN.
- ( Eugeo gasps )
- ( Kirito chuckles )
I GET IT!
YOU’RE WORRIED I’LL FIND A WAY
TO GET MY MEMORIES BACK
IN THAT TOWER, AREN’T YOU?
Eugeo: NO!
WELL, A LITTLE. ( sighs )
( Kirito chuckles )
WOULD YOU RELAX?!
Eugeo: DON’T!
STOP IT! LET ME GO!
Kirito: MAN, I TOLD YOU BEFORE
NOT TO WORRY, AND I MEANT IT.
WHETHER I GET MY MEMORIES BACK
OR NOT, WE MAKE A GREAT TEAM,
SO WE’RE STICKIN’ TOGETHER
’TIL THE END.
( Eugeo sighs )
STOP TREATING ME LIKE A KID.
IT’S NOT THAT I DON’T TRUST YOU
TO KEEP YOUR WORD.
YOU’VE ONLY MENTIONED IT
A MILLION TIMES SO FAR.
BUT WHEN I THINK
ABOUT HOW OUR JOURNEY
MIGHT BE COMING TO AN END,
I FEEL--I DON’T KNOW.
Kirito: THE FACT IS
IT’S GONNA END ONE DAY,
BUT DON’T FORGET
WHAT THAT’S GONNA MEAN.
YOU’LL GET ALICE’S MEMORY BACK,
AND THEN YOU’RE
GONNA TAKE HER HOME.
THERE’S ANOTHER GOOD THING
THAT’LL COME OUT OF IT.
YOU’LL GET TO PICK
ANOTHER CALLING.
IT MIGHT LAST
THE REST OF YOUR LIFE,
SO YOU BETTER START THINKING
ABOUT WHAT YOU WANT.
Eugeo: I THINK I STILL HAVE
A BIT OF TIME TO DECIDE.
I KNOW WHATEVER I PICK
WON’T HAVE ANYTHING TO DO
WITH WOODCUTTING.
( Kirito laughs )
NO SURPRISE THERE.
COME ON. LET’S GET GOING.
- Man: AS EXPECTED.
- ( both gasp )
Man: I HAVE TO ADMIRE
MY LADY ALICE’S WISDOM.
EVERYONE THOUGHT ESCAPE
FROM THAT PRISON WAS IMPOSSIBLE,
AND YET MY MENTOR PREDICTED IT.
Kirito: MENTOR?
Man: SHE ORDERED ME
TO CAMP OUT HERE FOR THE NIGHT
IN ANTICIPATION
OF YOUR BREAKOUT.
TO BE HONEST,
I WAS SKEPTICAL YOU’D SHOW UP,
AND, OH, HOW WRONG I WAS.
( Eugeo gasps )
AN INTEGRITY KNIGHT!
Kirito: HIS MENTOR IS ALICE?
Knight: THAT SAID,
YOU’LL BE RETURNING
TO YOUR GLOOMY PRISON SHORTLY
AFTER I ADMINISTER PUNISHMENT
FOR YOUR TRANSGRESSIONS.
YOU’VE BEEN WARNED,
SO PREPARE YOURSELVES.
Kirito: WELL,
HERE’S A WARNING FOR YOU, THEN.
IF YOU THINK WE’RE GONNA
GO BACK THERE WITHOUT A FIGHT,
- YOU’RE CRAZY.
- ( Knight gasps )
♪
( laughs )
SUCH NERVE!
IN HONOR OF YOUR BRAVADO,
I SHALL INTRODUCE MYSELF.
I AM THE INTEGRITY KNIGHT
ELDRIE SYNTHESIS THIRTY-ONE.
I DO NOT HAVE A TERRITORY
TO MY NAME YET,
AS I WAS FRESHLY SUMMONED
ONLY A MONTH AGO.
I DO HOPE THAT FACT
DOESN’T BOTHER YOU.
♪
( singing in Japanese )